<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms and Barplots</title>
      <link>/post/histograms-and-barplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/histograms-and-barplots/</guid>
      <description>HistogramsA histogram is an accurate graphical representation of the distribution of numberical data. It takes one group of numerical data and places it along the x-axis seperating it into bins. This allows the researcher to do initial analysis to see how the data is distributed.
For this example we will need these packages:
library(Lahman)library(dplyr)library(ggplot2)library(ggiraph)Now that we have the packages loaded in we want to query the database to select what data we want to visualize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISIS insurgency in Egypt&#39;s Sinai Peninsula</title>
      <link>/post/isis-insurgency-in-egypt-s-sinai-peninsula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isis-insurgency-in-egypt-s-sinai-peninsula/</guid>
      <description>The Egyptian military has struggled to maintain control of the Sinai Peninsula since the Egyptian revolution in 2011. The insurgency originally consisted Bedouin tribesmen, a nomadic group living in the desert regions of North Africa. The group has made multiple attacks upon the Egyptian military but have yet to claim allegiance to any specific group. Since 2014, a second insurgency known as Ansar Bait al-Maqdis, a jihadist extremist militant group, has claimed territory in the region and pledged allegiance to the Islamic State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coptic Christians of Egypt</title>
      <link>/post/the-coptic-christians-of-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-coptic-christians-of-egypt/</guid>
      <description>The Coptic Christians are the largest Christian community in the Middle East and are made up of approximately nine million Egyptian citizens, or roughly 10% of the population. The Copts can trace their lineage back St. Mark the Apostle and the creation of the Coptic Church sometime in the first century. In 451 AD, the Coptic Church split from the Christian community due to theological differences. Since this split, the Coptic community has been a major target for violence and persecution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Scatterplots in R</title>
      <link>/post/making-scatterplots-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-scatterplots-in-r/</guid>
      <description>A scatterplot is a graph in which the values of two variables are plotted along the two axes. This type of graphic is very important when looking for correlations between variables.
Let’s begin by loading that packages that we will need. For this example we will be using the Lahman database which contains baseball statistics going back over 100 years.
library(Lahman)library(dplyr)library(ggiraph)library(ggplot2)In this scatterplot we are going to compare the number of career homeruns hit to the number of strikeouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R for Basic Mathematics</title>
      <link>/post/using-r-for-basic-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-r-for-basic-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>AdditionLet’s try some basic addition in R.
x &amp;lt;- 7y &amp;lt;- 3x + y## [1] 10SubtractionNow let’s try subtraction.
x &amp;lt;- 7y &amp;lt;- 3x-y## [1] 4</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>